the MAD doctor is in.
Dr. Caligari is a fantasy, horror, science fiction
film directed by Stephen Sayadian.
Van Houten has shown signs of losing touch with reality, and her
husband discusses possible treatment with Dr.
Caligari, who says Mrs.
Van Houten has a disease of the libido.
Dr. Caligari, played by Madeleine Reynal.
Dr. Avol, played by Fox Harris.
Mrs. Van Houten, played by Laura Albert.
Ramona Lodger, played by Jennifer Balgobin.
Gus Pratt, played by John Durbin.
Les Van Houten, played by Gene Zerna.
Caligari is a 1989 American avant-garde horror erotic film co-written and directed by Stephen Sayadian and
starring Madeleine Reynal, Laura Albert, Gene Zerna, David Parry, Fox Harris and Jennifer Balgobin.
It is a quasi-sequel to the 1920 film The Cabinet of Dr.
The film details a disturbed doctor (the granddaughter of the original Dr.
Caligari) and her illegal experiments on her patients.
Originally and briefly billed as Dr.
Caligari 3000 when it debuted at select theaters in 1989,
the film promptly faded into obscurity.
Since it was released on VHS and limited Betamax format, the title has been Dr.
The film is considered a cult classic and has been shown
as a "midnight movie" at various times.
In the film, Dr.
Caligari conducts mindswapping experiments on unwilling
mental patients, in an attempt to cure them.
She succeeds only in transferring certain mental conditions
and character traits from one person to others.
The main themes explored in these experiments are human
cannibalism, nymphomania, and transvestism.
The film explores themes of asylum, surrealism,
suburbia, psychotronic, avant garde.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and thought_provoking.